# Daniel Mason

ALTAMONTE SPRINGS, FL 32701

(813) 528-6550 | daniel.i.msn@gmail.com | github.com/Daniel-J-Mason | www.all-thing.com

## Professional Summary

Mechanical Engineer with 5 years of experience in a fast-paced production environment. 3 years of software development skills with a passion for Java and Linux. Seeking to transition the technical-adjacent skills of mechanical engineering to full time software development.

#### Skills

- Languages: Java (2 years), Python(1 year)
- Frameworks and Libraries: Spring(1 year), JavaFX (1 year), PostgreSQL (1 year), MariaDB(6 months)
- Tools: Linux(3 years), Git(2 years), Docker(1 year), Maven(2 years), Gradle(6 months), Liquibase(6 months)

## **Projects**

#### Elite Dangerous Pilots Network (In-progress)

Backend Java Developer | April 2023 - Present https://github.com/ed-pilots-network

- Work with team of senior engineers to develop REST backend using: Spring, Kafka, Liquibase, Gradle, Git, Mybatis, PostgreSQL and Docker.
- Responsible for significant contribution to Spring stack and PostgreSQL schema design.
- Work group lead tasked with organizing backend development team objectives, responsible for communicating expectations with frontend and operation leads.
- Utilize code review to improve code quality and uphold design standards/architecture

# Work History

# Rev Group Inc.

Senior Mechanical Engineer | Orlando, FL | April 2023 - Current Mechanical Engineer | Orlando, FL | March 2018 - April 2023

- Proposed, designed, and implemented a custom JavaFX desktop application for the
  engineering department to compile all engineering-related files on the network to be
  searched in one place. Additional features: ability to find all trucks containing parts, part
  family tables, search histories.
- Created Transmittal Review software with JavaFX to compare CREO part BOM's to production packages to improve quality and minimize transcription errors.
- Designed over 300 ambulance exteriors across six independent brands for body fabrication in a fast-paced environment.
- Peer reviewed final release packages to ensure design quality prior to production start.
- Provided mentorship to several junior engineers through technical guidance, peer review, and hands-on training.
- Collaborated with sales, production, and other engineering departments to allow for proper planning and design.
- Provided solutions to critical production issues through hands-on analysis of ambulances at all stages of the production line.
- Contributed to improvements on ISO controlled engineering documents such as review documentation and brand design standards.
- Released several Engineering Change Notices to reduce annual cost and improve on brand design.

#### Education

**Bachelor of Science Mechanical Engineering** 

University of Central Florida

Orlando FL | December 2017